wwnorton.com 2019-05-25

# Privacy Policy | W. W. Norton & Company

**Effective Date: October 11, 2016**

This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) describes the practices (“Practices”) of W. W. Norton & Company, Inc., including its subsidiaries and certain affiliates (“Norton”, “we”, or “us”) concerning information we collect online. The Practices apply to all of the websites, applications, and other online services (collectively “Sites” and each individually a “Site”) that are owned or operated by Norton and link to the Privacy Policy, including Sites we operate on behalf of our authors and Sites we operate specifically for use by educators and students. By using our Sites, you are accepting the Practices described in the Privacy Policy. We may supplement the Practices from time to time by posting additional or superseding terms on specific Sites in connection with particular features of those Sites or in connection with particular online services or applications. For example, our collection and use of data from schools, faculty, school administrators and students may be more limited than what is permitted by the Practices described in this Privacy Policy. Please do not use our Sites if you do not agree to be bound by all of the terms of this Privacy Policy, or if you do not understand any aspect of the Privacy Policy, the Practices, or any other terms you find posted on any of the Sites. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information that we may collect offline, for example over the phone, by mail, or in person. 

**IF YOU ARE UNDER THE AGE OF 18 AND NOT ENROLLED IN ANY ACADEMIC COURSE THAT REQUIRES SUBMISSION OF CLASS WORK OR HOMEWORK VIA A SITE, YOU MUST HAVE THE PERMISSION OF A PARENT OR LEGAL GUARDIAN BEFORE YOU MAY ACCESS OR INTERACT WITH ANY OF THE SITES. Regardless of age, please read this Privacy Policy carefully to familiarize yourself with the Practices.**  
 ** _  
Personally Identifying and Non-Personally Identifying Information Distinguished_**

Personally identifying information is information (for example, your name, address, email address, telephone number, or credit card number) that individually identifies you. Non-personally identifying information (for example, your age, gender, or 5-digit zip code, unless applicable law provides otherwise) is information that does not personally identify you but may contain demographics such as your area of residence or your interests (as suggested by your uses of the Sites).  
 ** _  
Our Collection of Personally Identifying Information_**

The information that we collect about you is limited to non-personally identifying information unless you voluntarily provide us with personally identifying information. You may always choose to provide or withhold personally identifying information, but please bear in mind that in some instances such information will be required in order for you to participate in activities within the Sites. For example, we may ask you to provide your personally identifying information when you register for an account on the Sites, sign up to receive email newsletters for us, make a purchase on the Sites, enter a contest or sweepstakes, participate in surveys or special promotions, submit content on any part of the Sites where user-generated submissions are permitted, or knowingly identify yourself to us in order to request a specific interaction with us (for example, by submitting a help desk request or similar request for customer service). 

**The Sites are not intended for the use of individuals under the age of 13, and Norton does not knowingly collect personally identifying information from such individuals. PLEASE DO NOT ALLOW ANY CHILD UNDER 13 FOR WHOM YOU ARE RESPONSIBLE TO SEND US PERSONALLY IDENTIFYING INFORMATION.**

 ** _Our Collection of Non-Personally Identifying Information_**

Unlike personally identifying information, non-personally identifying information may be automatically collected by us (and our third-party providers) when you interact with the Sites or with emails you receive from us. For example, both we and our third-party providers may use technologies that automatically collect information about your computer or another device you use to access the Sites. Examples of this kind of information are IP addresses, geolocation information, unique device identifiers, browser types, browser languages, and other transactional information. We may also collect information about how you use the Sites via log files, clickstream data, reading history based on the pages you view, search terms and results, and other “traffic data” such as times and dates of access, software crash reports, session identification numbers and referring website addresses. If you choose to enable the location feature, some of our applications may deliver content based on your location, and the location information will be stored on your device and used by the app. If you choose to save a location-based search in your history, we will also store that information on our servers. We will not collect or store location information if you don’t enable the location-based service, or if an app does not include the location-based feature.   
**_  
Our Use of Cookies and Similar Technologies  
_**  
The term “cookies” refers to small text files that are stored on a user’s computer, phone or other device when the user visits online pages. Cookies record users’ actions and preferences. We use cookies to perform functions such as keeping track of users’ preferences, understanding how they use the Sites, and facilitating their payment transactions when they choose to make purchases on the Sites. Default browser settings usually accept cookies but can generally be modified to decline them. Refusing cookies may limit your ability to access the Sites. 

**_Targeted Advertising_**

The term “targeted advertising” refers to advertising that is served to users based on those users’ past browsing activities and behaviors. We may allow third parties such as network advertisers to use cookies and similar technologies that track your browsing activities to provide you with advertisements about goods and services of potential interest to you. These third-party technologies are not controlled by us and are not subject to this Privacy Policy. We do not authorize third parties to collect personally identifying information about you, and we do not give them access to your personally identifying information, except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Policy. Third parties may, however, track your internet usage anonymously over time and across other websites in their networks beyond our Sites. 

**_How We Use Information We Collect_**

The information we learn from users, including both personally identifying and non-personally identifying information, helps us to address business needs by, among other things, improving our users’ experience of the Sites. Examples of the ways in which we may use the information we collect from you include communicating with you about changes in our policies; keeping you abreast of products and services we offer; advising you of special events and promotions; providing you with products and services at request; communicating with you about your account or transactions; posting content by you, at your request, to Sites that permit such submissions; sending you newsletters; alerting you to third-party products and services that may interest you; providing you with personalized recommendations based on your preferences; serving you targeted advertising both on our Sites and elsewhere online; administering contests, sweepstakes, and surveys; optimizing our products, services and business operations; performing statistical, demographic and marketing analyses of users on the Sites and recipients of our emails; and detecting and investigating activities that may be unlawful or in violation of our policies. 

When you use more than one of our Sites, we may match information we collect from you through each of those Sites and combine that information into a single user record. We may also use and/or combine information we collect off-line or from third party sources to enhance and check the accuracy of your user records.

By using the Sites, you are consenting to these uses and others as specified herein, on the Sites, and in the Terms of Use.

 ** _How We Use Information We Collect When You Make Purchases On or Through Our Sites_**

When you make purchases on or through the Sites, you provide certain transactional information to us and to third-parties such as transaction processors and financial institutions. We use the information you provide in this connection primarily for the purpose of processing the transaction, but we may also use it for other lawful purposes including creating and managing your account, evaluating and improving our services, determining the effectiveness of our marketing, and performing certain forms of market and consumer research. Where other third parties, such as vendors who supply our software or perform web hosting and other services for the Sites, have access to your personally identifying information, they may not use such information for any purpose other than to provide services in connection with the Sites, unless they receive express permission from you.

 ** _Information We Share With Others_**

We do not sell or license personally identifying information to third parties except as required or permitted by law. Although we may provide your personally identifying information to our business partners as described below, we will not sell or rent your personally identifying information as part of a customer list or similar transaction unless you have given us your express permission to do so.

 **• Personally Identifying Information**

We may share your personally identifying information, on an as-needed basis, with the third party service providers we use to perform functions such as hosting, billing, marketing, analytics, customer service, and fraud protection on our behalf. These entities are obligated to maintain the confidentiality and security of your personal information and may not sell, distribute or alter this information or use it in any way other than to provide the requested services to the Sites. 

We use or disclose your personally identifying information if we are legally required to do so or if we believe in good faith that so doing is necessary (a) to be in compliance with law or legal process served on us or the Sites; (b) to protect or defend our rights or property, the Sites, or our users; or (c) in the event of an emergency, to protect our personal safety or the personal safety of our agents, the public, or users of the Sites. 

We may also share your personally identifying information with third parties with whom we do business. For example, we may share certain personally identifying information with our authors or promotional co-sponsors so that they can provide you with special offers, promotional materials, and similar materials that may be of interest to you. The Practices described in this Privacy Policy, and the Privacy Policy itself, govern our treatment of your personally identifying information but do not govern a third party’s use of the same information. Instead, third parties will collect, store, and use your personally identifying information according to their own privacy policies. You may withdraw your consent to our sharing of your personally identifying information with such third parties at any time by contacting us at privacy@wwnorton.com.  
 **  
• Non-Personally Identifying Information**

We may disclose or share your non-personally identifying information in any manner that we deem appropriate or necessary. By using the Sites, you agree that Norton may use, license and otherwise distribute any non-personally identifying information available on the Sites, whether collected by Norton or a third party, for market evaluation, product assessment and improvement, educational research, and any and all other marketing and commercial purposes as reasonably determined by Norton. 

**_Sites to Which This Privacy Policy Does Not Apply_**

This Privacy Policy and the Practices described in this Privacy Policy do not apply to resources and sites (“Third-Party Sites) not wholly operated or owned by Norton or not linked directly to this Privacy Policy, even Third-Party Sites that are accessible via links available on the Sites. Norton is not responsible for the privacy practices of any Third-Party Site, and our hosting of third-party content or linking to Third-Party Sites is not an endorsement by us of any such content or any Third-Party Site’s business practices or privacy policy. Please exercise reasonable caution in interacting with Third-Party Sites and be sure to review all applicable terms of use and privacy policies before determining whether or not to proceed. 

**_Student Privacy and Information Collected on Behalf of Educational Institutions_**

Some of the Sites provide course materials and services for educational institutions. We use the information collected on these Sites, including students’ personally identifying information, to support the educational institution, provide the services requested by course instructors and students, and inform students, faculty and administrators about products and services we offer that are relevant to them. Additional limitations may apply to our use and collection of student data, as posted on the Sites.   
**_  
Opting-Out and Other Choices_**

If you no longer want to receive commercial messages such as emails or newsletters from us, you may opt out, on a going-forward basis, at any time by following the “unsubscribe” button in any such communication or by emailing us at unsubscribe@wwnorton.com. We will make every reasonable effort to honor your opt-out request as soon as practicable following receipt. Please be aware, however, that you cannot decline to receive administrative messages from us such as important notices about our policies or practices relating to the Sites, and you may continue to receive such communications from us even after you have opted out of receiving commercial messages.   
**_  
Do Not Track Requests._**

“Do Not Track” is a privacy preference that you can set in your Internet search browser that sends a signal to a website that you do not want the website operator to track certain browsing information about you. However, because our Sites are not configured to detect Do Not Track signals from a user’s computer, we are unable to respond to Do Not Track requests. 

**_Security_**

Norton takes reasonable steps to protect and secure your personally identifying information. Unfortunately, however, no data storage or transmission system can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. You understand, acknowledge and agree that you transmit your personally identifying information to our Sites at your own risk. Please contact us immediately, as set forth in the “How to Contact Us” section below, if you have reason to believe that there has been a breach of any account that you may have with us, or that your interaction with any of the Sites is no longer secure.

 ** _Updates in this Privacy Policy_**

Updates and new developments in our Sites may result in changes in our Practices and this Privacy Policy, as may changes in applicable law. We will update this Privacy Policy as necessary to reflect changes in our Practices and will provide you with prominent notice on the Sites of any change that materially affects our use of personally identifying information. We will not, however, materially change our Practices in any way that would make them less protective of personally identifying information we have previously collected from you unless we obtain your express consent to do so. Please check the “effective date” above to see when this Privacy Policy was last revised. Your use of the Sites following any update in the Privacy Policy means that you have accepted the revised Privacy Policy, including any changes made in that update. 

**_Governing Law_**

Norton is a corporation organized under the laws of the State of New York in the United States of America, and the Sites are operated in, and targeted primarily to users located in, the United States. Please do not submit personally identifying information to us if you are uncertain whether this Privacy Policy conflicts with applicable privacy law in the location from which you access the Sites.

 ** _California Users  
_**  
Pursuant to California Civil Code Section 1798.83, California users may have the right to request and receive certain information in connection with the disclosure of their personally identifying information to third parties for direct marketing purposes as permitted by the Practices described in this Privacy Policy. To make such a request, not more than once per calendar year, please send us email at privacy@wwnorton.com. We reserve the right not to respond to requests submitted other than in accordance with this section. 

**_How to Contact Us_**

Please direct any questions about this Privacy Policy to us by mail or email as follows: 

Mail:

Online Privacy  
Attention: Customer Service  
National Book Company  
800 Keystone Industrial Park  
Dunmore, PA 18512

Email: Privacy@wwnorton.com
